sandiegocounty.gov 2019-09-03

# Security and Privacy Policies

### Information That May Be Collected And How It May Be Used

If you do nothing during your visit to the County website but browse or download information, we may automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

The Internet Protocol (IP) address and domain name used, but not the email address. The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet Service Provider or directly to your computer. We use the IP address to direct Internet traffic to you;   
The type of browser and operating system you used and your connection speed;   
The date and time you visited this site;   
The webpages or services you accessed at this site; and   
The website you visited prior to coming to this website.   
The information we collect or store may be used to improve the content of our Web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Our website logs do not identify anyone personally, and we make no attempt to link them with the individuals that browse the County website. If during your visit to the County website or mobile app you send an email, participate in a survey or report an issue, the following additional information will be collected:

Email correspondence: The email address and contents of the email;   
Surveys: Any information you volunteered in response to a survey.   
Web or mobile app: Any information submitted as well as geolocation data permitted by the device and/or technical specifications such as, but not limited to, camera type, photo metadata, or device model and operating system.

The information collected may not be limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. The information is retained in accordance with the County's policies. We may use your email to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the email to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information and issues reported would be used for the purpose designated.

### Personal Information and Choice

"Personal information" is information about an individual that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes personal identifiers such as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or IP address is not considered personal information.

We will not collect personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an e-mail or participating in a survey). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of the County's website.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, County rules and regulations, the State's Information Practices Act of 1977 or the Federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it from disclosure.

Children are not eligible to use services that require submission of personal information, and we require that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us. This includes submitting personal information to the County as part of a user profile or personalization profile. If you are a minor, you can use these services only if used together with your parents or legal guardians. If you are a minor, you should seek guidance from your parents.

### Public Disclosure

We strive to protect personally identifiable information by collecting only information necessary to deliver our services. All information that may be collected at this site or through a web or mobile application becomes public record that may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption in law exists.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and any County ordinance or other law governing the County's disclosure of records, the County ordinance or other applicable law will control.

### Access and Correction of Personal Information

You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe is in error by submitting a written request that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. See Contact Information section.

### Cookies

**What Is A Cookie?**

A cookie is a small data file which may include an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website's computers and may either be used only during your session (a "session" cookie) or may be stored on your computer's hard drive (a "persistent" cookie). Cookies can contain data about user movement during the visit to the Web site. If your browser software is set to allow cookies, a website can send its own cookie to you.

**Why Are Cookies Used On Websites?**

Cookies are a mechanism for maintaining continuity during a user's visit to a website. They allow data to be maintained for users' benefit as they navigate a site. This is referred to as "session" or "management" cookie. These cookies go away when you terminate your visit to the website as they are maintained only in your browser's active memory during your session. Cookies may also be stored on your computer so that you can be recognized by a website on subsequent visits. They are read by the website that sent them whenever you re-visit the website. They are often used on websites that require you to login so that you can avoid having to enter all of your login information every visit. They may store information on your unique identifier and the areas of the website you have visited before. These cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive after you have left your website visit and consequently are often referred to as "persistent" cookies.

**Choices About Cookies**

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.)

**County Practices Regarding Cookies**

Presently, the County uses persistent cookies on some of its web applications.

### Security

The County has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the entire operating environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management.

Our cybersecurity program is based on the same security standards that are required of the Federal and California State Governments as well as the financial payment industry. Protections include:

  * Developing Information Security Policies, Standards Guidelines and Controls.
  * Implementing countermeasures in aggregated layers that provides for a holistic cybersecurity defense.
  * Conducting risk and vulnerability assessments and implementing risk mitigation measures.
  * Promoting employee information and cybersecurity awareness training.
  * Providing proactive threat protections, monitoring for malicious activity, and incident management.
  * Maintaining compliance with Federal and State statutes and regulation.

For information about what you can do to protect yourself and your family from being a victim of cyber-crime, the US-CERT.GOV website has numerous tips and publications on topics like _Keeping Children Safe Online, Banking Securely Online, Shopping Safely Online, Avoiding Online Gaming Risks, Using Portable Devices, Secure Social Networking, Securing Your Computer and Home Networks_ and many others.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice. This information should not be construed as warranting as failproof the security of information provided through County-supported websites.

### Disclaimer

San Diego County has links to other websites. These may include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the County website and this Privacy Policy will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

### San Diego County Contact Information

To offer comments about San Diego County websites, or to comment about the information presented in this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at: [ **Webmaster@sdcounty.ca.gov**](mailto:Webmaster@sdcounty.ca.gov).
